山姆威尔・塔利
琼恩・雪诺
守夜人事务官
凯特琳・徒利
史塔克夫人
塔斯的布蕾妮
凯特琳的护卫
詹姆・兰尼斯特
“弑君者”
罗柏・史塔克
北境之王
泰丽莎
女护士 瓦兰提斯贵族
瑞卡德・卡史塔克
卡霍城伯爵
艾莉亚・史塔克
泰温的侍酒
贾昆・赫加尔
布拉佛斯的无面者
热派
詹德利
鲁温
临冬城学士
欧莎
女野人
布兰・史塔克
瑞肯・史塔克
阿多
卢斯・波顿
恐怖堡伯爵
科林
断掌
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
叮当衫
骸骨之王
丹妮莉丝・坦格里安
风暴降生 龙之母
乔拉・莫尔蒙
“大熊” 流亡骑士
提利昂・兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 代理首相
乔佛里・拜拉席恩
铁王座之王
曼登・穆尔
御林铁卫
波德瑞克・派恩
提利昂・兰尼斯特的侍从
史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
狭海之王
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
托曼・拜拉席恩
洛拉斯・提利尔
“百花骑士”
泰温・兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护
■
双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译     北落师门
翻译    守誓剑
翻译    火吻的梅丽珊卓
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译    加文・维斯特林
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
校对    卡萨布兰卡
校对    suerhine
派
Pyke
克
城
派
Pyke
克
城
复校    托曼・兰尼斯特
复校    杰诺斯・史林特
Violet_Rosa
临冬城 Winterfell
精校   龙的命根子
监制    旧镇老翁
后期    旧镇老翁 poplar
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)
绝境长城 the Wall
衣柜军团力作《权力的游戏：漫画小说》实体书即将发售
最新进度请关注新浪微博@指文图书        敬请期待！
颤抖海 Shivering Sea
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治・R・R・马丁
魁尔斯Qarth
权力的游戏
第二季 第十集
衣柜字幕组
第十集  "Valar Morghulis"
派席尔
首席学士
波德
Pod.
波德！
Pod!
波德瑞克・派恩
提利昂・兰尼斯特的侍从
把波隆或者瓦里斯找来
Find Bronn or Varys.
告诉他们 我跟派席尔国师在一块
Tell them I am here with Maester Pycelle.
告诉他们 我活得好好的
Tell them I am very much alive.
遵命 大人
Yes, My Lord.
要点喝的止疼吗？
Would you like something for the pain?
后来怎么了？
What happened?
叛国恶贼史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
The murderer and traitor Stannis Baratheon
被令尊大人亲自率兵打了个落花流水
suffered a stunning defeat at the hands of your father.
这是哪儿？
Where am I?
这是您的新房间
These are your new chambers.
可能有点窄
A little cramped, perhaps,
但你本来也不占多大地儿 对吧？
but you don't need much room, do you?
你不再是首相了
You are no longer Hand of the King.
哦
Oh.
辛苦你了
For your trouble.
泰温・兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护
我 安达尔人和先民的合法国王
I, Joffrey of the House Baratheon, first of my name,
七国统治者
the rightful King of the Andals
珊莎・史塔克
暨全境守护
and the First Men,
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
乔佛里・拜拉席恩
铁王座之王
拜拉席恩家族的
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
乔佛里一世
and protector of the Realm,
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
在此宣布 我的外祖父
do hereby proclaim my grandfather
泰温・兰尼斯特为君临之拯救者
Tywin Lannister the savior of the city
洛拉斯・提利尔
“百花骑士”
玛格丽・提利尔
培提尔・贝里席
“小指头” 财政大臣
并任其为国王之手
and the Hand of the King.
谢谢您  陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
培提尔・贝里席大人 请上前来
Lord Petyr Baelish, step forward.
兰尼斯特与提利尔两大家族的联合
For your good service and ingenuity
多亏你的尽职尽责和足智多谋
in uniting the Houses of Lannister and Tyrell,
是以 我宣布将赫伦堡及其所有封地和赋税恩赐给你
I declare that you shall be granted the castle of Harrenhal...
你的子孙后代
With all its attendant lands and incomes
将世代继承此等荣耀
to be held by your sons and grandsons
万世不辍
from this day until the end of time.
陛下 我承蒙恩赏 无以言谢
You honor me beyond words, Your Grace.
这就设法弄几个子孙出来
I shall have to acquire some sons and grandsons.
洛拉斯・提利尔爵士
Ser Loras Tyrell.
提利尔家族救驾有功
Your House has come to our aid.
不仅仅是我
The whole realm is in your debt,
整个王国都欠你们的情
none more so than I.
提利尔家族若对我有所请求 尽管告诉我
If your family would ask anything of me, ask it
我将有求必应
and it shall be yours.
陛下
Your Grace,
我有一个妹妹玛格丽
my sister Margaery,
她的丈夫不久前死于非命
her husband was taken from us before...
但她仍为处子身
She remains innocent.
恳请您赐予本家族无上荣耀
I would ask you to find it in your heart
让我们两家偕手联姻
to do us the great honor of joining our Houses.
玛格丽小姐 您可愿如此？
Is this what you want, Lady Margaery?
乐意之至 陛下
With all my heart, Your Grace.
我远道来此 只为向您倾吐爱慕之情
I have come to love you from afar.
关于您英明和勇武的传说
Tales of your courage and wisdom
片刻未离我耳畔
have never been far from my ears.
早已深入我心
And those tales have taken root deep inside of me.
同样 关于你容貌和风姿的传说我也早有耳闻
Well, I too have heard tales of your beauty and grace,
只不过那些传说
but the tales
还不足以描绘出您的美丽优雅
do not do you justice, My Lady.
如能与你相爱 实属荣幸
It would be an honor to return your love,
无奈我已有婚约在身
but I am promised to another.
国王必须信守承诺
A King must keep his word.
陛下 您的御前会议认为
Your Grace, in the judgment of your small council,
迎娶已经明正典刑的叛徒之女
it would be neither proper nor wise
既为不智 亦为不妥
for you to wed the daughter of a man beheaded for treason,
更何况此时她的哥哥正举叛旗
a girl whose brother is in open rebellion
公然反抗铁王座
against the throne as we speak.
为了王国的荣耀
For the good of the realm,
御前会议恳请您……
your councilors beg you...
解除跟珊莎・史塔克的婚约
to set Sansa Stark aside.
- 玛格丽！  - 王后玛格丽！
- Margaery! - We want Margaery!
我愿意参考你们的意见
I would like to heed your wishes
听取人民的愿望
and the wishes of my people,
但我的婚约立于诸神之前
but I took a holy vow.
陛下
Your Grace,
诸神见证的婚约的确神圣庄严
the Gods do indeed hold betrothal solemn,
但您的父亲――受神荣宠的先王
but your father, blessed be his memory,
订立此婚约之时
made this pact before the Starks
史塔克家叛迹未显
revealed their falseness.
我就此事咨询过总主教
I have consulted with the High Septon
他向我保证  由于他们的叛国罪行
and he assures me that their crimes against the realm
您对他们的任何誓约义务均已失效
free you from any promise you have made to them
诸神可鉴
in the sight of the Gods.
诸神圣裁
The Gods are good.
令我得遂心愿
I am free to heed my heart.
洛拉斯爵士 迎娶令妹将是无上之喜
Ser Loras, I will gladly wed your sweet sister.
你将成为我的王后
You will be my Queen
从今日起 我对你的爱
and I will love you from this day
将矢志不渝
until my last day.
小姐
My Lady.
我深表同情
My sincerest condolences.
他们说的对―― 我配不上他
They're right-- I'm not good enough for him.
你实在不该这么说
You shouldn't say that.
对他来说 配不上的东西也有很多用处
You'll be good enough for many things.
例如他会随心所欲毒打你
He'll still enjoy beating you.
而你既然已经成了真正的女人
And now that you're a woman,
他就能用其他方式占有你
he'll be able to enjoy you in other ways as well.
但如果他不娶我了――
But if he's not marrying me--
那么他就会放你回家？
He'll let you go home?
乔佛里可不会轻易放走手上的玩具
Joffrey's not the sort of boy who gives away his toys.
你有一颗温柔的心
You have a tender heart,
和你母亲当年一样
just like your mother did at your age.
我能在你身上看到她的影子
I can see so much of her in you.
她就像我的亲姐姐
She was like a sister to me.
为了她
For her sake,
我会帮你 让你回家
I'll help get you home.
现在 君临就是我的家
King's Landing is my home now.
你仔细看看周围
Look around you.
这里每个人都是骗子
We're all liars here.
而且每一个都比你高明
And every one of us is better than you.
萝丝
妓女
进来
Come in.
请随意
Make yourself comfortable.
这看上去也太拘束了
That doesn't look very comfortable.
来吧 看着我
Here, watch me.
亲爱的 不用这样
No need for that, my dear.
你确定？
You sure?
男人都喜欢看这些
Most men like what they see.
我和别的男人不一样
I'm not like most men.
别的男人也都这么说
That's what most men say.
如果你和别的男人想要的不一样
If you don't want what most men want,
那请告诉我 你希望让我做什么呢
then you'd better tell me what you'd like me to do.
我希望你能告诉我 贝里席大人给的工作
I would like you to tell me if working for Lord Baelish
是否是你愿意做的工作
has been all you'd hoped it would be.
我们见过？
Have we met?
如果见过 你会不记得吗？
You wouldn't remember me if we had?
我见了不少男人
I meet a lot of men.
我想他们都被你记住了
And I think you remember all of them.
我想这是对你真正天赋的浪费
I think your true talents are wasted on them.
大人 您太好心了
You're very kind, My Lord.
请允许我报答您吧
Allow me to return the favor.
你很害怕
You're afraid.
怎么？我下面又没什么危险的玩意儿
Why? Nothing dangerous down there.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
而且和你的现任雇主不同
And, unlike your current employer,
我会为我的手下提供保护
I protect those who work for me.
也不为了满足贵族老爷的某些怪癖 虐待他们
I don't abuse them to satisfy royal whims
或强迫他们互相虐待
or force them to abuse each other.
你怎么知道这些事的？
How do you know about that?
你不是说你知道我是谁吗
I thought you said you knew who I was.
有什么可以效劳的 瓦里斯大人？
What can I do for you, Lord Varys?
小指头看你的时候
Littlefinger looks at you
看到的是一个长着洞的赚钱机器
and sees a collection of profitable holes.
而我却看到一个潜在的合作伙伴
I see a potential partner.
- 我怕他 - 哦 这很自然
- I'm afraid of him. - Oh, you should be.
他可是个危险的家伙
He's a dangerous man.
不过每个人都有各自的弱点
But everyone has their weaknesses.
你的老板自认为把弱点隐藏得很好
Your current employer hides his very well,
但其实并非如此
but not as well as he thinks.
塔斯的布蕾妮
凯特琳的护卫
詹姆・兰尼斯特
“弑君者”
你还是个处女 猜的对吗？
You're a virgin, I take it?
快走
Walk.
你的童年一定很悲惨
Childhood must have been awful for you.
你是不是比其他男孩都高一头？
Were you a foot taller than all the boys?
他们是不是嘲笑你 给你起外号？
They laughed at you, called you names?
有些男孩喜欢挑战自己
Some boys like a challenge.
肯定有那么一两个试图强上大块头布蕾妮
One or two must have tried to get inside big Brienne.
- 是有那么一两个 - 啊
- One or two tried. - Ah.
可是你把他们都打跑了
But you fought them off.
不过没准你希望他们中的某个能打败你
But maybe you wished one of them could overpower you,
把你推倒在地 撕掉你的衣服
fling you down, tear off your clothes.
可惜他们都不够强壮
But none of them were strong enough.
- 我倒是挺强壮 - 我对你没兴趣
- I'm strong enough. - Not interested.
你当然有
Of course you are.
你一定想知道做女人是什么滋味
You'd love to know what it feels like to be a woman.
啊 “贱人与狮子同床”
Ah. "They lay with lions."
依我看是旅店小妹
Tavern girls, I'd say.
八成侍奉的是我老爸的士兵
Probably served my father's soldiers.
也许有一位给了他们一个吻 一段情
Maybe one of them gave up a kiss and a feel.
然后就落得如此下场
That's how they earned this.
为自由而战的北方战士的杰作啊
The glorious work of the northern freedom fighters.
你效忠史塔克家族 一定倍感荣耀
Must make you proud to serve the Starks.
我不效忠史塔克家族 我只效忠凯特琳夫人
I don't serve the Starks. I serve Lady Catelyn.
晚上梦见她们的时候记得用这话安慰自己
Tell yourself that tonight when they swing in your dreams.
- 你要干嘛？ - 埋葬她们
- What are you doing? - Burying them.
我们不宜在此久留 得赶紧回到河上去
We shouldn't stay here. We should get back on the river.
我觉得这些女人能够理解--
I think these women would understand if--
我才不在乎你怎么觉得
I don't care what you think.
我没把匕首落在这
I didn't leave it here.
快给我松绑
Untie me now.
我给了你去砍断绳索
I gave it to you to cut the rope, and now I don't
然后就找不到了
have my dagger no more.
就是说你肯定把匕首弄丢了
So unless it got stuck in your ass on its way to your cunt,
除非你用它自慰的时候卡在屁股里了-- 喂！
it stands to reason that it's gone-- whoa!
你们在这里做什么？
What's your business here?
押送囚犯
Traveling a prisoner.
你是个娘儿们 一个娘儿们！
You're a woman. A woman!
哈哈 我操！
Well, fuck me!
如果你们笑够了--
If you've quite finished up--
行 行 我们这就走
All right, we'll be going.
喂 等等
Whoa, whoa.
你是哪边的
Who do you fight for?
史塔克那边的
The Starks.
他犯了什么罪
What did he do?
鬼知道呢 这年头显然吃东西都犯罪了
Apparently eating is now a crime. Who knew?
胡说 偷东西就是犯罪
No, stealing is a crime.
挨饿就不算 这就是公正
But it's not a crime to starve. That's justice for you.
- 你要把他带到哪里去？ - 奔流城
- Where are you taking him? - To Riverrun.
干嘛去奔流城？
Why Riverrun?
偷了徒利家的东西 自然要在他们的地牢里度余生
Steal from the Tullys, it's their dungeons you rot in.
- 干嘛不杀了他？ - 就因为偷了一头猪？
- Why not kill him? - For stealing a pig?
我只是奉命行事
I don't give the orders.
他一定对某人很重要
He must be important to someone.
让你押送他？这能有多重要？
Sending him with you? How important could he be?
好吧 你走你的
All right, have it your way,
小姐
m'lady.
- 我认识你吗？ - 你到过烙印城？
- Do I know you? - Have you been to Ashemark?
- 没有 - 那你不认识我
- No. - Then you don't know me.
你有没有去过盐石城的河边集市？
Do you ever go to the river market at Salt Rock?
- 离烙印城很近吗？ - 不
- Is it near Ashemark? - No.
我没去过那里
I've never been there.
你们对这些美女作何评价？
What do you think of these beauties?
我希望你当初给她们一个干脆
I hope you gave them quick deaths.
是啊 有两个死得蛮干脆
Two of them we did, yeah.
等等
Wait.
我认出你了
I do know you.
他是詹姆・兰尼斯特
That's Jaime Lannister.
这事怎么没人告诉我
I wish someone had told me.
早知就不用去偷那头该死的猪了
I wouldn't have had to steal that pig.
如果真是弑君者 我肯定知道
If this is the Kingslayer, I think I'd know about it.
你怎么知道弑君者长什么样？
How do you know what the Kingslayer looks like?
我参加了呓语森林之战 我见过他
I was at Whispering Wood. I saw him.
他们从树林中把他拖出来 扔到国王面前
They dragged him out of the woods and threw him down before the King.
他不是弑君者 让你失望了
He's not the Kingslayer. Sorry to disappoint you.
他要真是 我只带着他的脑袋就够了
If he was, I'd only be traveling his head.
我有一个问题问你们俩
I have a question for you both.
我要你们同时回答
And I want you to answer it at the same time.
我数到三 你们一同开口
I count to three, you both answer.
他到底叫什么名字
What's his name?
一
One.
二 三
Two. Three.
两个干脆的
Two quick deaths.
他们可是史塔克的人
Those were Stark men.
我说了我不效忠史塔克家族
I don't serve the Starks.
我只效忠凯特琳夫人
I serve Lady Catelyn.
我向她保证把你带到君临
I told her I'd take you to King's Landing,
我说到做到
and that's what I'm going to do.
呆着别动
Stay.
罗柏・史塔克
北境之王
凯特琳・徒利
史塔克夫人
瓦德・佛雷可不能随意冒犯
Walder Frey is a dangerous man to cross.
我知道
I know that.
那你还要这么干？
And you mean to do it anyway?
我爱她
I love her.
我知道你觉得这很重要
I know that seems important to you.
这就是对我很重要
It is important to me.
我嫁给你父亲的时候他并不爱我
Your father didn't love me when we married.
我们几乎不认识彼此
He hardly knew me or I him.
爱情不是从天而降的
Love didn't just happen to us.
那是我们这么多年来
We built it slowly over the years,
从一点一滴中收获的
stone by stone,
有你一点 有你的兄弟姐妹们一点
for you, for your brothers and sisters,
有我们每个人一点
for all of us.
它虽然不像在树林里偷欢那么刺激
It's not as exciting as secret passion in the woods,
但却更加坚定
but it is stronger.
更加长远
It lasts longer.
这就是我与某个佛雷家族女孩之间
And that is what would be in store for me
将要发生的故事吗
with one of Walder Frey's daughters,
- 就像你和父亲一样？ - 有什么不好呢？
- what you and father had? - Why not?
就因为她不漂亮？
Because she's not beautiful?
因为她没有异域风情 让你没有激情？
Because she's not exotic and exciting?
你现在一定要跟我争个明白 还不是因为这婚事是你一手安排的
Now you're arguing just to argue because you arranged it.
你当时也同意了
And you agreed to it.
你向他发过誓
You gave him your word.
对自己的誓言不负责任 你的手下也会有样学样
Treat your oaths recklessly and your people will do the same.
你父亲一辈子活着只为了一件事--
If your father lived his life for one thing--
我父亲已经死了
My father is dead.
而我的母亲没有资格
And the only parent I have left has no right
指责任何人不负责任
to call anyone reckless.
史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
狭海之王
你说你在火焰中看到了我的胜利
You said you saw my victory in the flames.
我是看到了
I did.
梅丽珊卓
“红袍祭司”
- 现在也一样 - 火焰撒谎了
- I still see it. - The flames lied.
- 我现在就跟化外蛮人一样
And I'm no better than a savage
盲目地相信一个火神
trusting in a Fire God.
我在黑水湾上为你的神明而战
I fought for your God in Blackwater Bay.
我带领部下来到七层地狱门外
I led my men to the gates of the Seventh Hell
手下的兄弟们被活活烧死 图个什么？
as their brothers burned alive, and for what?
被泰温・兰尼斯特和提利尔家族从后方包夹
Attacked from behind by Tywin Lannister and the Tyrells.
如果你在火焰中都看到了 为什么不警告我？
If you see so much in your flames, why didn't you warn me?
光之王只给了我惊鸿一瞥
The Lord of Light only allows me glimpses.
你说你是他的代言人
You claimed to speak for a God.
你会因为输掉一场战役而放弃整个战争吗？
Will you quit the war just because you've lost a battle?
你以为自己对战争了解多少
You talk about war as if you understand it.
比你要早很多
I've been fighting far longer than you.
是吗？让我瞧瞧你怎么作战
Have you? Show me how you fight.
让我瞧瞧
Show me.
你的神明现在在哪里？
Where's your God now?
他不来救你？
Will he save you?
你的神明在哪？
Where is your God?
在你心里
Inside you.
我谋杀了我的弟弟
I murdered my brother.
是我们联手杀了他
We murdered him.
让我分担您的压力吧。
Share the weight with me.
他又不是你弟弟
He wasn't your brother.
战争才刚刚开始
This war has just begun.
它将持续好几年
It will last for years.
数以千计的人会死在你麾下
Thousands will die at your command.
你会背弃效忠你的人
You will betray the men serving you.
背弃你的家庭
You will betray your family.
背弃一切你所珍惜的东西
You will betray everything you once held dear.
而这一切都是值得的
And it will all be worth it
因为你就是圣焰之子
because you are the Son of Fire.
你就是光明的战士
You are the Warrior of Light.
你会把这些伪王一个接一个地扫除
You will sweep aside this pretender and that one.
成为真正的君王
You will be King.
你夸夸其谈 但是...
You promise these things, but...
你自己也不清楚
you don't know.
我们都不清楚
None of us know.
我可以展示给你看
Let me show you.
凝视火焰 陛下
Look into the fire, my King.
看
Look.
我只看见火
I see fire.
仔细看
Keep looking.
看见了吗？
Do you see?
你看见了吗 陛下？
Do you see, my King?
是的
Yes.
席恩・葛雷乔伊
我会宰了他
I will kill that man.
我不管被多少箭矢射中
I don't care how many arrows they feather me with,
被多少长矛刺穿
how many spears they run through me,
鲁温
临冬城学士
但我倒下前一定手刃那个吹号角的王八蛋
I will kill that horn-blowing cunt before I fall.
他们想让你知道你被包围了
They want you to know you're surrounded.
我知道自己被包围了
I know I'm surrounded.
我知道 因为我到城垛上去看过了
I know that because I stood on the battlements
我看到我被包围了
and saw I was surrounded.
他们不想让你睡觉
They don't want you to sleep.
他们想先榨干你的元气 然后--
They want to sap your spirit before--
谢谢了 知无不言的老秃子
Thank you, wise bald man.
谢谢你教导我什么是围城
Thank you for explaining siege tactics to me.
我父亲没来信？
No word from my father?
没有
No.
派更多信鸦
Send more ravens.
您已经杀了所有信鸦
You killed all the ravens.
我第一次看见临冬城...
The first time I saw Winterfell...
我第一次看见临冬城
The first time I saw Winterfell,
它像是早已在此
it looked like something that had been here for
矗立千年
thousands of years
而且在我死后
and would be here for thousands of years
它仍将在此矗立千年
after I was dead.
我看着它想
I saw it and I thought,
“难怪奈德・史塔克能够镇压我们的叛乱
"of course Ned Stark crushed our rebellion
干掉我的兄弟
and killed my brothers.
因为面对土生土长在这里的人我们毫无胜算”
We never stood a chance against a man who lives here."
史塔克大人想尽办法让它成为你的家
Lord Stark went out of his way to make it your home.
是的 抓我的人对我很好
Yes, my captors were so very kind to me.
你很喜欢对我提起此事
You love reminding me of that.
在这个冷飕飕的茅坑里
Everyone in this frozen pile of shit
每个人都喜欢对我提起此事
has always loved reminding me of that.
你知道做了俘虏还被人告知要感恩戴德
You know what it's like to be told how lucky you are
要顶礼膜拜俘虏你的人
to be someone's prisoner?
是什么滋味吗？
To be told how much you owe them?
然后当你回到生父身边…
And then to go back home to your real father...
我一定宰了那孙子
I will kill that man.
我向淹神发誓
I swear it to the Drowned God,
向旧神 新神
the Old Gods, the New Gods,
所有该死的神灵发誓
to every fucking God in every fucking heaven,
我一定宰了那孙子
I will kill that man.
席恩 听我说
Theon, listen to me.
我为临冬城效忠
I serve Winterfell.
现在您是临冬城主
Now Winterfell is yours.
我理应辅佐您
I'm bound by oath to serve you.
那你的建议是什么 可以信赖的朋友？
And what's your counsel, trusted friend?
逃跑
Run.
城外有五百号北方人
500 Northmen wait outside the walls.
你只有二十人
You have 20 men.
不可能胜利
You can't win.
等到夜色降临 就逃走吧
Wait for nightfall and run.
无处可逃
There's nowhere to run.
我逃不回铁群岛
I'd never make it back to the Iron Islands.
就算侥幸成功
And even if I did, even if by some miracle
穿过封锁线 返回家园
I slipped through the lines and made it home,
也会被视为懦夫
I'd be a coward.
临阵脱逃的葛雷乔伊
The Greyjoy who ran.
这是家族的羞耻
The shame of the family.
不要回家
Don't go home.
加入守夜人吧
Join the Night's Watch.
当一个人披上黑衣...
Once a man has taken the Black...
就可免受律法的制裁
he's beyond reach of the law.
过去的一切罪行都会被原谅
All his past crimes are forgiven.
我也走不到长城
I won't make it to the Wall.
甚至走不出临冬城城门十尺
I won't make it 10 feet past the Winterfell gates.
有办法的
There are ways.
临冬城下有暗道
Hidden passageways built so the Lords of Winterfell
供临冬城主在需要时逃走
could escape.
前路确实艰险
The road will be dangerous.
但是如果运气好...
But with a little luck...
守夜人是个古老而荣耀的组织
the Night's Watch is an ancient, honorable order.
你在那儿有机会
You'll have opportunities there.
在睡梦中被琼恩・雪诺抹了脖子的机会
The opportunity for Jon Snow to cut my throat in my sleep.
偿还你所作所为的机会
The opportunity to make amends for what you've done.sleep.
我做得太多了 是不是？
I've done a lot, haven't I?
我都想不到自己会做这样的事情
Things I never imagined myself doing.
我认识你很多年了 席恩・葛雷乔伊
I've known you many years, Theon Greyjoy.
你不是你要伪装的那种人
You're not the man you're pretending to be.
还不是
Not yet.
也许你是对的
You may be right.
但我已无法重新选择
But I've gone too far to pretend to be anything else.
达格摩
裂颚
都听见了吗？
You hear that?
那是北方人的集结号
That's the mating call of the Northmen.
他们想干了我们
They want to fuck us.
哈 我都好久没痛快干过了
Well, I haven't had a good fuck in weeks.
正想来一次呢
I'm ready for one.
每个铁种都能抵大陆上的一打好汉
They say every Ironborn man is worth a dozen from the mainland.
没错！
Aye!
- 你们相信这说法？ - 是的
- You think they're right? - Aye.
弟兄们 今天就是我们的死期
We die today, brothers.
我们死在血泊中
We die bleeding from 100 wounds
浑身上下伤痕累累 被插满箭头枪尖
with arrows in our necks and spears in our guts,
但我们的吼声将回荡不息
but our war cries will echo through eternity.
人们将为临冬之战引吭高歌
They will sing about the battle of Winterfell
哪怕铁群岛淹没在浪涛之下
until the Iron Islands have slipped beneath the waves.
每个男人 女人和孩子 都会知道我们的名字
Every man, woman, and child will know who we were
知道我们坚持战斗了多久
and how long we stood.
阿加 葛马
Aggar and Gelmarr;
威克斯 乌兹
Wex and Urzen;
斯提吉 还有黑罗伦--
Stygg and Black Lorren--
当铁种战士踏上海疆城和仙女城的海岸
Ironborn warriors will cry out our names
他们将高呼我们的名字
as they leap onto the shores of Seagard and Faircastle.
对！
Aye!
- 哺乳的母亲将以我们的名字为婴儿命名 - 对！
- Mothers will name their sons for us. - Aye!
偷情的少女将把她们的伴侣想象成我们的模样
Girls will think of us with their lovers inside them.
对！
Aye!
谁要是能宰了那个吹号的混蛋
And whoever kills that fucking horn-blower
就在派克岛上为他立个铜像！
will stand in bronze above the shores of Pyke!
对啊！
Aye!
- 逝者不死！ - 逝者不死！
- What is dead may never die! - What is dead may never die!
冲啊！
Ah!
说个没完了
Thought he'd never shut up.
多动人的演讲
It was a good speech.
真不愿打断啊
Didn't want to interrupt.
怎么回事？
What is this?
你们在做什么？
What are you doing?
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
走吧
Come on.
我为何要相信你？
Why should I believe you?
我为何要说谎呢？
Why would I lie about it?
为了挑拨我和姐姐的关系
To create strife between my sister and me.
之前你们之间满满的都是爱？
Where before there was nothing but love.
曼登・穆尔爵士奉你姐姐之命杀你
Ser Mandon Moore tried to kill you on your sister's orders.
如果不是你勇敢的侍从
If it weren't for your Squire's bravery,
你早已死了
you'd be a dead man.
- 波德 － 是的 大人？
- Pod. - Yes, My Lord?
如果我一周之内两次求你救我性命
Would it be excessive of me
会不会太过分了？
to ask you to save my life twice in a week?
不会 大人
No, My Lord.
好孩子
You're a good lad.
告诉波隆 我需要四名最忠诚的金袍子
Get Bronn, tell him I want four of his most loyal
日夜守在门外
Gold Cloaks outside my door at all times.
恐怕你的队长朋友
I'm afraid your friend has been relieved
已经被解职了
of his command of the City Watch.
金袍子现在被牢牢握在你父亲
The Gold Cloaks are now firmly in the hands of your father
或者你姐姐的手心里
or your sister.
他们的主子换得勤
It varies from cloak to cloak.
- 那就叫我的山区部落氏族 - 他们已经回家了
- Then my hill tribesmen. - Have gone home.
你父亲提供了慷慨的回报
Your father paid them quite handsomely.
恐怕我们将有一段时间不能见面了
I'm afraid we won't be seeing each other
大人
for some time, My Lord.
怕我拖你下水？
Don't want to swim too close to a drowning man?
我以为我们是朋友
And I thought we were friends.
我们是
We are.
波德瑞克 麻烦你
Podrick, would you mind?
雪伊
珊莎的侍女
许多人都知道 如果没有你
There are many who know that without you
这座城市必将沦陷
this city faced certain defeat.
虽然国王不会授予你荣誉
The King won't give you any honors,
史书也不会提到你
the histories won't mention you,
但是我们不会忘记
but we will not forget.
来吧 波德瑞克
Come along now, Podrick.
亲爱的
My love.
感谢你前来
It was good of you to come.
感谢？
Good of me?
我当然要来
Of course I come.
- 我想看看你 - 相信我 你会后悔的
- I want to see you. - Believe me, you don't.
你自己照过镜子吗？
Have you looked?
那我就是第一个看到的
I will be the first.
怎样？
Well?
糟透了
You are a mess.
我是个侏儒 也是个恶魔
I'm a monster as well as a dwarf.
你该向我索要双倍的钱
You should charge me double.
你认为我是为钱而来？
You think I'm here for money?
这是我们的安排
That was the arrangement we made.
我付钱给你 你负责向我撒谎
I pay you and you lie to me.
哦 我是个可怜的小富人
Aw, I'm a poor little rich man
没人爱我 所以我总爱说笑话
and nobody loves me, so I make jokes all the time
并花钱雇人大笑
and pay them to laugh.
去你的银子
Fuck your money.
我们逃走吧
Let's leave.
- 逃走？ - 逃出君临
- Leave? - Leave King's Landing.
他们曾试图杀你 一定会再度尝试
They tried to kill you. They will try again.
上战场 杀敌人--
Going into wars, fighting soldiers--
你干这个太差了
you're terrible at this.
我们坐船去潘托斯 再也不回来
Let's take a boat to Pentos and never come back.
你不属于这里
You don't belong here.
我们在潘托斯能干啥？
What would we do in Pentos?
大吃 大喝
Eat, drink,
做爱 生活
fuck, live.
我想和你同去
I want to go with you.
那就来啊
So do it.
你父亲 姐姐 所有这些坏人
Your father, your sister, all these bad people,
都不能阻挡你
they can't stop you.
忘记他们 和我走吧
Forget about them. Come with me.
我不能
I can't.
我确实属于这里
I do belong here.
对付这些坏人
These bad people
就是我擅长的
are what I'm good at.
说赢他们 想赢他们
Outtalking them, outthinking them.
就是我平时做的
It's what I am.
而且我喜欢做这个
And I like it.
比我之前做过的任何事情都喜欢
I like it more than anything I've ever done.
你要走吗？
Are you going to leave?
你的记忆力被狗吃了
You have a shit memory.
我就是你的 你就是我的
I am yours and you are mine.
七神之下
In the sight of the Seven,
我在此缔结两颗灵魂
I hereby seal these two souls,
让他们从此合二为一 永结同心
binding them as one for eternity.
望着彼此 一起来诵读这神圣的誓言吧
Look upon one another and say the words.
泰丽莎
瓦兰提斯女护士
天父 铁匠
Father, smith,
战士 圣母
warrior, mother,
少女 老妪 陌客……
maiden, crone, stranger...
- 诸神为证 我之身心 唯属于他… - 诸神为证 我之身心 唯属于她…
- I am hers and she is mine... - I am his and he is mine...
我愿与之相守白头 于此立誓 直至永远
from this day until the end of my days.
鬼魂之殿 卡丽熙 大家都知道
乔拉・莫尔蒙
“大熊” 流亡骑士
丹妮莉丝・坦格里安
风暴降生 龙之母
科瓦罗
血盟卫
守卫在哪里？
没有守卫
男巫们用巫术杀人 而不是刀剑
让他们来试试
这是个谜语吗？
Is this a riddle?
卡丽熙
你打算用这些戏法来吓唬我么？
Are you trying to frighten me with magic tricks?
你要见我？来吧 我就在这里
You want me? Here I am.
难道你会害怕一个小姑娘？
Are you afraid of a little girl?
热派
艾莉亚・史塔克
泰温的侍酒
詹德利
贾昆・赫加尔
布拉佛斯的无面者
他是怎么找到我们的？
How did he find us?
你在这里干嘛？
What are you doing here?
等你
Waiting for you.
你怎么知道我们会从这里走
How did you know we'd come this way?
某人为你做了这么多 女孩看在眼里
After all the things you have seen,
女孩难道没有什么别的疑问吗？
this is your question?
你是如何杀掉那些守卫的？
How did you kill those guards?
这很难么？
Was it hard?
如果你精于此道 杀几个人要比女孩换个名字还简单
No harder than taking a new name if you know the way.
教我 我要学 我也想学到你的那些本事
Show me how. I want to be able to do it, too.
女孩如果要学 就必须跟某人一起走
If you would learn, you must come with me.
去哪里？
Where?
背井离乡 远渡狭海 直到布拉佛斯
Far and away across the Narrow Sea to Braavos.
我的舞蹈老师就来自布拉佛斯
My dancing master was from Braavos.
成为一名水舞者固然是件了不起的事情
To be a dancing master is a special thing,
但是如果要成为一名无面者――
but to be a faceless man--
可就是另外一码事了
that is something else entirely.
女孩嘴边还念着许多名字――
A girl has many names on her lips--
乔佛里 瑟曦 泰温・兰尼斯特
Joffrey, Cersei, Tywin Lannister,
伊林・派恩 “猎狗”
Ilyn Payne, the Hound.
只需把名字献给红神
Names to offer up to the Red God.
红神就是债主 他们必须死
She could offer them all one by one.
我想学
I want to.
可是我没法跟你走
But I can't.
我要去找我的妈妈和哥哥
I need to find my brother and mother.
还有我姐姐
And my sister.
我必须找到她
I need to find her, too.
那某人必须离开
Then we must part.
某人还有其他任务在身
A man has duties as well.
给
Here.
这是什么？
What is it?
一枚珍贵的硬币
A coin of great value.
够买一匹马的吗？
Could it buy a horse?
某人给你这枚硬币不是叫你去买马
It is not meant for the buying of horses.
那是买什么？
Then what good is it?
如果有朝一日女孩要再见某人
If the day comes when you must find me again,
只需将这枚硬币交给任何一个布拉佛斯人
just give that coin to any man from Braavos
然后对他们说
and say these words to him,
“Valar Morghulis.”
"Valar Morghulis."
Valar Morghulis.
别走 贾昆
Please don't go, Jaqen.
贾昆已死
Jaqen is dead.
再说一遍 Valar Morghulis.
Say it again. Valar Morghulis.
Valar Morghulis.
很好
Good.
再见 艾莉亚・史塔克
Farewell, Arya Stark.
欧莎
女野人
欧莎 你在干嘛？
Osha, what are you doing?
布兰・史塔克
阿多
瑞肯・史塔克
告诉我们 去你的房间里能找什么药？
Tell us what medicine to get from your chambers.
- 我们会让你好起来的  - 我感觉挺好的
- We'll make you better. - I feel just fine.
屋子全被烧了 一切都被夷为平地
They burned it down. They burned everything.
不全是 至少你们还安然无恙
Not everything. Not you.
但是他们随时都会回来 你们必须走
But they may come back. You have to go.
穿上最暖和的冬衣
Put on your warmest clothes.
带上所有能找到的食物 往北边逃
Pack as much food as you can carry and go north.
往北走可不对头
North's the wrong way.
他们的妈妈和哥哥可是在南方啊
Their mother and brother are south.
可是我们不知道到底在哪
We don't know where.
唯一可以确定的是南方的敌人比这里更多
There are too many enemies in the South.
去长城 去找琼恩
Go to the Wall to Jon.
他会照顾你们 保护你们 然后通知你们的母亲
He'll look after you and let your mother know you're safe.
我不想离开你
I don't want to leave you.
我也不想离开你
No more than I want to leave you.
要知道 你可是我接生出来的
I pulled you into the world.
你们俩都是
Both of you.
从那以后 我们朝夕相处
I've seen both your faces almost every day since.
想想这些 我是多么、多么的幸运啊
And for that, I consider myself very, very lucky.
快走 和阿多一起走
Go now with Hodor.
快 走吧
Go on.
我在这里会没事的
I'll be right here.
阿多
Hodor.
欧莎
Osha.
你必须保护好他们
You must protect them.
因为只有你能保护他们了
You're the only one who can.
或许有朝一日 你会不得不为此与你的族人们刀兵相见
You may have to protect them against your own kind.
我对我的族人们可没有多少感情
I've got no great love for my own kind.
我去帮你找罂粟花奶吧
I'll get you milk of the poppy.
告诉我 它们在哪里
Tell me where to find it.
我不需要罂粟花奶
I don't want milk of the poppy.
做的干脆点
Do it quickly.
卓戈卡奥
丹妮莉丝・坦格里安的亡夫
雷戈
丹妮莉丝・坦格里安的亡子
我生命中的月亮
这是黑魔法 就像之前把你害死的巫术一样
从此与我阴阳两隔  我甚至来不及……
或许我也死了吧 可谁又说得准呢
没准我们此刻都在夜之国度里
又或者是我没有死 我不会丢下生命中的月亮 独自前往夜之国度的
“去死吧”我对马神说 然后我就这样大模大样的回来了 来和你重聚
这听起来是才像你能做出的事情呢
又或许 只是一场梦吧 你梦到我 我梦到你……
……我不知道
管他呢 把这些问题留给那些长着瘦胳膊的聪明人去想吧
生命中的月亮
你是我唯一的念想……
……也是我唯一的渴望
如果这一切都是梦境
…我宁愿长眠 谁若敢将我唤醒我便杀了他
无论沧海桑田 世事变迁
Until the sun rises in the west
就算太阳西升东落
and sets in the east,
就算川泽干涸枯竭
until the rivers run dry
就算群山化为齑粉 如烟飘散 愿我们永远不要醒来 永远
and the mountains blow in the wind like leaves.
他们想念你 龙之母
They miss their mother.
俳雅・菩厉
男巫
他们惟愿与你相依
They want to be with you.
你是否同怀此念？
Do you want to be with them?
毋庸置疑
You will be.
自幼龙破壳之时起
When your dragons were born,
魔法亦随之重生
our magic was born again.
魔力强大 与生俱来
It is strongest in their presence.
得汝相伴 则更甚之
And they are strongest in yours.
毋庸置疑 你们将长相为伴
You will be with them,
历尽冬夏 遑论春秋
through winter, summer,
季复一季 年复一年
and winter again.
千载万劫 此情难却
Across a thousand thousand seasons
直到洪荒再临 时光永绝
you will be with them.
你们都会恒久相随 永世不分
And we will be with you until time comes to an end.
“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝 欢迎回家
Welcome home, Daenerys Stormborn.
这里不是我的家
This is not my home.
我的家在狭海的另一头
My home is across the sea
那里有我的子民 他们对我翘首以盼
where my people are waiting for me.
他们可要等上好久了
They will be waiting a long time.
龙焰
Dracarys.
我们必须在日落之前赶到
We should be there by sundown.
今晚可不会像昨天那样欢乐
Won't be a fun night for you.
曼斯可是非常擅长让乌鸦唱歌的呦
Mance knows how to make crows sing.
琼恩・雪诺
守夜人事务官
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
叮当衫
骸骨之王
科林
断掌
如果你懂得如何取悦曼斯 或许你会撑过今晚
If you know what to say, you might just make it
活到明天
through the night.
如果你装哑巴的话 可就离死不远了
Not talking's not the way to go.
当心哟
Careful with that.
可别砍到自己了
You might cut yourself.
你从没用过剑 是吧？
Never swung a sword before, have you?
看起来就像个玩拨浪鼓的毛孩子
You look like a baby with a rattle.
够了
Enough of that!
- 住手！- 为啥 叛徒？
- Stop! - Why, traitor?
好让你邀请曼斯・雷德去黑城堡做客？
So you can give Mance Rayder an invitation to Castle Black?
让他们打
Let 'em fight.
就这样？你就这点能耐？
That's it? That's what you can do?
小兔崽子
You little shit.
这是你那叛徒老爹教你的么？
Your traitor father teach you that?
还是你那婊子老娘遗传的？
Or was it your whore mother?
我们是长城上的卫士
We are the Watchers on the Wall.
你可以去跟曼斯说了
You can tell Mance
这位是杀掉断掌科林的人
that's the man who killed Qhorin Halfhand.
- 烧掉尸体 - 是
- Burn the body. - Aye.
你可不会希望这位变成尸鬼回来找你的
You don't want this one coming back for you.
过来 琼恩・雪诺
Come along, Jon Snow.
让我们去见见塞外之王吧
Time to meet the King-Beyond-The-Wall.
札罗・赞旺・达梭斯
魁尔斯“十三巨子”之一
多莉亚
丹妮莉丝・坦格里安的侍女
这是――？
What the--?
卡丽熙 求你
Khaleesi, please.
他说你绝不可能活着离开魁尔斯
He said you'd never leave Qarth alive.
过来
Come.
空无一物
Nothing.
谢谢你 札罗・赞旺・达梭斯
Thank you, Xaro Xhoan Daxos.
多谢你教给我这宝贵的一课
Thank you for teaching me this lesson.
我现在已是魁尔斯之王
I am King of Qarth.
我可以帮助你了 真的 我可以了
I can help you now, truly help you.
我们可以一起夺回铁王座
We can take the Iron Throne.
- 我会给你一千艘船 - 我求您了 卡丽熙
- I'll bring you 1,000 ships. - Please, Khaleesi, I beg you.
您梦到的那些绝非镜花水月 有朝一日终将实现
All that you have dreamed is within your reach!
求您了 卡丽熙
I beg you, please!
- 卡丽熙 - 求您了 求您了
- Khaleesi. - Please! Please!
卡丽熙
- Khaleesi!
谎言 都是谎言
It's all a lie.
这看起来货真价实
Looks real enough to me.
够买一条船么？
Real enough to buy a ship?
是的 一条小船
Aye, a small ship.
把金子和珠宝都拿走
我还以为我们北上是来打野人的呢
I thought we were coming north to fight wildlings.
葛兰
守夜人游骑兵
“忧郁的”艾迪
守夜人事务官
山姆威尔・塔利
这是山羊的吗？
Is this goat?
是麋鹿的
It's moose.
人类绝不应该住在
People shouldn't live anywhere
任何需要靠烧大便取暖的地方
you need to burn shit to keep warm.
好吧 你要是看到了树 记得告诉我一声
Well, you see a tree, let me know.
其实你要是退一步去想想这些事
If you step back and think about it,
我是说 有关吉莉的那些事 真的还是挺耐人寻味的――
the thing about Gilly that's so interesting is--
- 靠 要死人了 - 不会有假 真的会死
- Just bloody kill me. - No, truly.
我觉得吉莉这人还挺耐人寻味的
The thing about her that I find so interesting is that
即使她被卡斯特那样对待
after all that Craster's done to her,
她仍然憧憬着希望 幻想着自己的生活会变得更好
she's still got hope that life might get better.
你觉得吉莉这人挺耐人寻味 无非是因为
The thing about Gilly that you find so interesting
她跟你蹦了几个单词儿
is that she said six words to you.
我觉得你这人也挺耐人寻味的
And the thing about you that I find so interesting
因为寻不着味……
is absolutely nothing.
听 号响 一定是琼恩和断掌
It's Jon and the Halfhand.
他们回来了
They're back.
两声号响 是野人 野人来犯
Two blasts is wildlings.
走 让我们一起去好好教训下他们
You're not fighting them alone. Come on.
三声号响？
Three blasts?
快跑！
Run!
等下！等等我！
Wait! Wait for me!
葛兰！
Grenn!
艾迪！
Edd!
衣柜字幕组出品